Finding Aid for Alvin M. Bentley Papers 1935-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Michigan-British Honduras (Belize) Partners of the Alliance 1966-1969
  - MacLellan, John W (Box 66)
  - MacMillan, J.W., 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Orr, Edgar, 20 folders (Box 66)
  - Topper, Robert (Box 67)
  - Varner, Durward (Box 67)
  - Walker, Fred, 4 folders (Box 67)
  - Walker, Orville, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Listings of Membership & Board (Box 67)
  - Membership Drive, correspondence, 7 folders (Box 67)
  - Membership Drive, notebooks, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Membership dues, 5 folders (Box 67)
  - Contributions (Box 67)
  - Inactive memberships (Box 67)
  - Budget (Box 67)
  - Fund Raising (Box 67)
  - Investment Conference February 6-7, 1968
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 67)
    - Correspondence with Romney (Box 67)
    - Memoranda (Box 67)
    - Invitations (Acceptances/regrets) (Box 67)
    - Reservations (Box 67)
    - Finances (Box 67)
    - Exhibits-Displays (Box 67)
    - Reference materials (Box 67)
    - Tour by George C. Price, Premier of Belize (Box 67)
    - Tripartite Economic Survey (Box 67)
    - War on Hunger (Box 67)
    - Final Report (Box 67)
  - Michigan-Belize News Reports (Box 68)
  - Agriculture Committee (Box 68)
  - Commerce Committee
    - Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Memoranda (Box 68)
    - Agency for Industrial Development (Box 68)
    - Industry (Box 68)
    - Tourism (Box 68)
    - Volunteers for International Technical Assistance (Box 68)
  - Cultural Committee (Box 68)
  - Education Committee
    - Correspondence, 4 folders (Box 68)
    - Meeting November 22, 1966 (Box 68)
    - Peace Corps (Box 68)
    - People-to-People Program (Box 68)
  - Policy Committee
    - Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Memoranda (Box 68)
  - Public Health and Medical Education Committee, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - Public Relations Committee
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 68)
    - Membership Brochure (Box 68)
    - Memoranda (Box 68)
    - Speakers Bureau (Box 68)
  - Research Committee
    - Correspondence & Memoranda (Box 68)
    - Oceanography (Box 68)
  - Scholarship Committee
    - Correspondence, 4 folders (Box 68)
  - Survey Team
    - Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Reports (Box 68)
  - Welfare & Womens' Service Organization
    - Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Memoranda (Box 68)
  - Notebook: Special Reports on Michigan/Belize Partnership (Box 68)
  - Notebook: Story of the Michigan/Belize Partnership (Box 68)
  - Printed material (Box 69)
  - Clippings (Box 69)
- Board of Regents 1966-1969
  University of Michigan Board of Regents (6.8 linear ft.; 1966-1969) consists of correspondence with U-M presidents Harlan Hatcher and Robben Fleming, with other members of the Board of Regents and with key university administrators. In additional there is an extensive topical file of correspondence, clippings, and printed materials arranged alphabetically and pertaining to university departments and units, issues coming before the regents, and student affairs.
  - Appointment to the Board
    - Correspondence (Box 69)
    - Congratulations
      - A-E (Box 69)
      - F-L (Box 69)
      - M-P (Box 69)
      - R-Z (Box 69)
    - Clippings (Box 69)
  - Correspondence
    - Robben Fleming, 5 folders (Box 69)
    - Paul G. Goebel (Box 70)
    - Harlan Hatcher (Box 70)
    - Herbert Hildebrandt, 3 folders (Box 70)
    - Barbara Newell (Box 70)
    - Wilbur Pierpont (Box 70)
    - Michael Radock (Box 70)
    - Arthur Ross (Box 70)
    - Allan Smith (Box 70)
    - Erich Walter (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous, 13 folders (Box 70)
  - Topical File
    (correspondence, printed and clippings)
    - Admissions (Box 70)
    - Alumni Association (Box 70)
    - Alumni Association-Family Camp (Box 70)
    - Alumnae Council Committee for Continuing Education of Women Center (Box 70)
    - Annuities Association (Box 70)
    - Appropriations, 3 folders (Box 70)
    - Architecture & Design, College of (Box 70)
    - Athletic Department
      - Athletic Director Appointment (Box 70)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Box 70)
      - Intramural Athletics (Box 70)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 70)
      - Physical Education (Box 70)
      - Structural Reorganization (Box 70)
    - Authorizations & Investment Procedures (Box 71)
    - Black Students (Box 71)
    - Budget, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Buildings (Box 71)
    - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (Box 71)
    - Cinema Guild (Box 71)
    - Civil Rights (Box 71)
    - Classified Research (Box 71)
    - Clements Library (Box 71)
    - Computers (Box 71)
    - Curriculum/Counseling (Box 71)
    - Dean of Women (Box 71)
    - Dearborn Campus (Box 71)
    - "Dionysus in 69" (Box 71)
    - Discrimination-Fraternities and Sororities (Box 71)
    - Distinguished Alumni (Box 71)
    - Dormitories (Box 71)
    - Dormitory Bonds (Box 71)
    - Educational Radio (Box 71)
    - Educational Television (Box 71)
    - Eighteen-year old vote (Box 71)
    - Endowed professorships (Box 71)
    - Endowments (Box 71)
    - Enrollments (Box 71)
    - Executive Officers Salaries (Box 71)
    - Expenditures (Box 71)
    - Fairlane Estate (U-M-Dearborn) (Box 71)
    - Faculty-miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Faculty Center (Box 71)
    - Faculty-Student Relationships (Box 71)
    - Financial Aid (Box 71)
    - Fraternities (Box 71)
    - Fifty-five Million Dollar Fund
      - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Calendar (Box 71)
      - Campaign Briefs (Box 71)
      - Clippings (Box 71)
      - Personal Contributions-Major Gifts (Box 71)
    - Graduate School (Box 71)
    - Graduate School of Government (U-M-Dearborn) (Box 71)
    - Great Lakes Research Institute (Box 72)
    - Governing Boards (Box 72)
    - Health Service (Box 72)
    - History Department (Box 72)
    - Honorary Degrees (Box 72)
    - Housing, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Inauguration of Robben Fleming (Box 72)
    - Institute for Defense Analysis (Box 72)
    - Institute for Social Research (Box 72)
    - International Christian Leadership, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Investigations of Students (Box 72)
    - Labor Negotiations, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Legislative Relations (Box 72)
    - Legislative Bills (Box 72)
    - Major Gifts
      - Correspondence with Corporations (Box 72)
      - Correspondence-miscellaneous (Box 72)
      - Committee Meetings (Box 72)
    - Medical School (Box 72)
    - Michigan Association for Higher Education (Box 72)
    - Michigan Daily, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Michigan Historical Collections (Box 72)
    - Michigan Memorial-Phoenix Project (Box 72)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 72)
    - Motor Vehicles, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Presidential Selection Process (Box 72)
    - Property Bonds Sales (Box 72)
    - Public Act No. 124-State Funding (Box 72)
    - Public Act No. 240-State Funding (Box 72)
    - Regents Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 73)
    - Regents-General (Box 73)
    - Regents-Citizen's Advisory Committee (Box 73)
    - Regents meetings, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Regents invitations, 10 folders (Box 73)
    - Regents-reference materials, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - ROTC (Box 73)
    - Research (Box 73)
    - Residential College, 3 folders (Box 73)
    - Revision of By-laws (Box 73)
    - School of Natural Resources (Box 74)
    - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA) (Box 74)
    - Sesquicentennial (Box 74)
    - Sororities (Box 74)
    - State Board of Education (Box 74)
    - State Plan for Higher Education, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Steering Committee (Box 74)
    - Students
      - General (Box 74)
      - Selective Service, 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Curfew (Box 74)
      - SDS, 6 folders (Box 74)
      - Demonstrations (Box 74)
      - Government, 5 folders (Box 74)
      - Housing (Box 74)
      - Power (Box 74)
      - Organizations, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Teaching Fellows (Box 74)
    - Theater Fund-Raising Study Committee (Box 74)
    - Tuition and Dormitory (Box 75)
    - Tuition Status: Residency (Box 75)
    - University Hospital, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Use of University Facilities (Box 75)
    - Workmen's Compensation (Box 75)
  - University of Michigan Reports (Box 75)
- Miscellaneous Bentley Activities 1960s
  Other Bentley Activities (2 linear ft.; 1960s) is a miscellaneous series relating to Bentley's diverse philanthropic and organizational interests. This alphabetically arranged series has extensive material on the Historical Society of Michigan, the National Conference on Citizenship, the state Republican Party, and various Owosso and Shiawassee County groups. This series includes documentation of Bentley's studies in the history department of the University of Michigan.
  - Administrative Assistant's Activity Reports September 1963-December 1964 (Box 75)
  - American Friends of the Captive Nations 1964-1969 (Box 75)
  - American Good Government Society
    - 1961, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - 1962 (Box 75)
    - 1963 (Box 75)
    - 1964 (Box 75)
    - 1965, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 75)
  - Capitol Hill Club 1960-1963 (Box 75)
  - Colleges and Schools
    - Asheville School 1960-1969, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Cleary College 1957-1968 (Box 75)
    - Detroit Institute of Technology 1961-1966 (Box 75)
    - Greenhills School 1968 (Box 75)
    - Harker Preparatory School 1964-1965 (Box 75)
    - Maryglade College-Knight of Chanty Award 1962, 1965 (Box 75)
    - Nazareth College 1965-1969 (Box 75)
    - Northwood Institute 1964-1968 (Box 75)
    - Olivet College 1961-1962 (Box 75)
    - Owosso College 1963-1969 (Box 76)
    - Riverside Academy 1964-1966 (Box 76)
    - University of Detroit President's Cabinet 1967-1968 (Box 76)
  - Congressional Reapportionment 1964 (Box 76)
  - Council for Christian Leadership 1954-1964, 2 folders (Box 76)
  - Educational Organization for Freedom Studies, Inc. (Ulysses Boykin) (Box 76)
  - Employment Enterprises Development Corporation 1965-1966 (Box 76)
  - Great Lakes Development Project 1965 (Box 76)
  - Greater Michigan Foundation 1966-1968 (Box 76)
  - Historical Society of Michigan
    - Board of Trustees Correspondence 1964, 1967-1969 (Box 76)
    - Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Minutes 1965, 1967-1968 (Box 76)
    - Committee Assignments 1966-1967 (Box 76)
    - General Correspondence
      - 1961-1966 (Box 76)
      - January-June 1967 (Box 76)
      - July-September 1967 (Box 76)
      - October-December 1967 (Box 76)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 76)
    - Heritage Day-Michigan Week 1961-1967 (Box 76)
    - Liaison with Michigan Historical Commission Committee 1966-1967 (Box 76)
    - R.E. Olds Mansion 1965-1966 (Box 76)
    - Tuomy House 1967-1968 (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 76)
  - International Affairs 1960-1961 (Box 76)
  - Labor-reference material (Box 76)
  - Masons: Bentley's Reception of 33 1967
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 76)
  - Michigan Federation of College Republicans
    - 1964-1965 (Box 76)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 76)
  - Michigan Historical Commission 1961-1968 (Box 76)
  - Michigan Society for Mental Health 1965-1968, 2 folders (Box 76)
  - Michigan State Chamber of Commerce 1966-1967 (Box 76)
  - Michigan Young Americans for Freedom 1965-1966 (Box 76)
  - National Conference on Citizenship
    - 1960 (Box 76)
    - 1961 (Box 76)
    - 1962 (Box 76)
    - 1963 (Box 76)
    - 1964 (Box 76)
    - 1964-"Plans for the Future" notebook (Box 76)
    - 1965 (Box 76)
    - 1966 (Box 76)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 76)
  - Owosso Chamber of Commerce 1961-1968, 2 folders (Box 76)
  - Owosso Memorial Hospital 1961-1968 (Box 77)
  - Owosso Savings Bank 1964-1969 (Box 77)
  - Owosso Traffic Safety Committee 1966-1969
    - Correspondence (Box 77)
    - Committee members (Box 77)
    - Minutes (Box 77)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 77)
    - Clippings (Box 77)
  - Project HOPE
    - National Committee
      - Annual reports (Box 77)
      - Correspondence
        - 1963 (Box 77)
        - 1964 1966 (Box 77)
      - SS HOPE Staff Rosters (Box 77)
      - "HOPE/News" 1963-1966 (Box 77)
      - HOPE Press releases 1963-1966 (Box 77)
      - Miscellaneous publicity materials (Box 77)
      - Audio-tape re Project HOPE (Box 77)
    - Michigan Committee
      - Correspondence, memos and reports
        - John H. Bock (Michigan Field Director)
          - 1964-1965 (Box 77)
          - 1966-1967 (Box 77)
        - Singe Karlstrom (executive assistant) 1963 (Box 77)
        - C. David Armstrong 1965-1966 (Box 77)
      - Press releases and newsletters 1965-1966 (Box 77)
    - Local Committees
      - Ingham County-Greater Lansing Area 1963-1966 (Box 77)
      - Muskegon County 1963, 1965 (Box 77)
      - Oakland County 1964 (Box 77)
      - Washtenaw County 1963-1964 (Box 77)
      - Wayne County-Greater Metropolitan Detroit
        - 1962-1963 (Box 77)
        - 1964-1966 (Box 77)
        - Women's Division (Box 77)
    - Clippings
      - 1963-1964 (Box 77)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 77)
  - Republican Party
    - Educational Candidates Committee 1965-1966, 1968 (Box 77)
    - Michigan 1964-1969 (Box 77)
    - National 1962-1967 (Box 77)
    - National Convention Delegate Letters 1968 (Box 77)
    - Report: Republican and Democrat Party Turnout 1940-1960 (Box 77)
    - Report: Republican Vote for State Offices 1940-1960 (Box 77)
    - Task Force on Problems and Goals 1965 (Box 78)
  - Salvation Army (Michigan) 1964-1967 (Box 78)
  - Seventh Congressional District
    - Correspondence 1963-1964 (Box 78)
    - Notebook: Market Opinion Research Company-Political Study of Congressional Contenders in Seventh District (Genesee, Shiawassee & Lapeer counties) 1964 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee Community College Local Study Group 1967-1968 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee County Historical Society
    - Correspondence 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Newsletters 1967-1969 (Box 78)
    - Paper, "Shiawassee County-The Last 25 years" by Martha Woodard 1923 (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous 1962-1968 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee County: Lincoln Day Banquet March 1966 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee County Republican Committee 1964-1966 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee County: Technical-Vocational Study Committee
    - Committee materials, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Committees (Box 78)
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 78)
    - Final Study Report
      - Chapters 1-3 (Box 78)
      - Chapters 4-8 (Box 78)
      - Additional information (Box 78)
    - Lists of names (Box 78)
    - Meetings (Box 78)
    - Memoranda (Box 78)
    - Michigan Dept. of Public Instruction (Box 78)
    - Questionnaires (Box 78)
    - Reference materials (Box 78)
    - Speech and news release outlines (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee River Association 1965, 1968 (Box 78)
  - Shiawassee Wildlife Refuge 1967 (Box 78)
  - Sleeping Bear Dunes National Seashore 1961 (Box 78)
  - Split ticket voting reference material (Box 78)
  - Supreme Court Amendment League 1968 (Box 78)
  - University of Michigan Graduate School career 1960s
    - Correspondence with history dept. (Box 78)
    - History 644: Comparative Studies in Modern Western History (Box 78)
    - History 689: Studies in Diplomatic History of U.S. (Box 78)
    - History 770: Seminar in American History Since 1876 (Box 78)
    - Political Science 771: Seminar in Problems of American Foreign Policy (Box 79)
- Invitations
  Invitations (1.5 linear ft.; 1960-1968) is a small series of invitations received during Bentley's political campaigns of the 1960s and his tenure as a member of the U-M Board of Regents.
  - February 1960-1963, 21 folders (Box 79)
  - 1963-1968, 21 folders (Box 80)
- Speeches
  Speeches (0.5 linear ft.; 1961-1966 and 1968) is a separate series of Bentley's speeches from the 1960s. Other speeches are scattered as indicated in the various other series.
  - 1961 (Box 80)
  - 1963 (Box 80)
  - 1964 (Box 80)
  - 1965 (Box 80)
  - 1966, 1968 (Box 80)
- Foreign Service files
  Foreign Service Files (0.1 linear ft.; 1941-1950) is a small series of passports and related kinds of documents that Bentley received in his career with the Foreign Service.
  - 1941-1946 (Box 81)
  - 1947-1950 (Box 81)
- Personal Correspondence (general and miscellaneous)
  Personal correspondence (2.9 linear ft.; 1939-1969) consists of communications with family and friends, mainly from the period of the 1950s and 1960s. Some of the files detail Bentley's various travels. There is a file from 1968 documenting his relationship with Richard Nixon in his presidential campaign.
  - 1947-December 1961, 22 folders (Box 81)
  - Mary P. Hopkins 1961 (Box 81)
  - 1962-1963, 8 folders (Box 82)
  - Calvin A. DeViney 1963 (Box 82)
  - Financial 1963 (Box 82)
  - 1964 A-Z (Box 82)
  - 1964 (Box 82)
  - 1965 (Box 82)
  - 1965 Testimonial dinner (Box 83)
  - 1966 (Box 83)
  - 1966 Puerto Rico trip (Box 83)
  - 1967 (Box 83)
  - 1967 Arizona trip (Box 83)
  - 1967 Europe trip (Box 83)
  - 1968 (Box 83)
  - 1968 Bernice E. White (Box 83)
  - 1968 Richard M. Nixon (Box 83)
  - 1969 A-Z (Box 83)
  - 1969 (Box 83)
- Personal Files
  - Biographical and genealogical (Box 84)
  - Childhood mementos belonging to AMB (Box 84)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 84)
  - Guest register, 3 volumes (Box 84)
- Scrapbook and Clippings
  Scrapbooks/Clippings (9.7 linear ft.; 1935-1969) documents all phases of Bentley's career as well as on those issues that he considered of importance in his various campaigns.
  - circa 1917-1958 (Volume 1)
    (scattered dates)
  - 1935-1937. Scrapbook re high school and Michigan Daily activities (Box 84)
  - 1939 European trip (Volume 2)
  - Undated, 1940s (clippings) (Box 84)
  - 1947. Budapest (clippings) (Box 84)
  - 1948. Budapest (clippings) (Box 84)
  - 1949. Budapest (clippings) (Box 84)
  - 1950-1952. Scrapbook of speeches (Box 84)
  - 1951 (clippings) (Box 85)
  - 1951 (scrapbook of articles) (Box 85)
  - 1952 (clippings), 2 folders (Box 85)
  - 1952 (Owosso Argus Press clippings) (Box 85)
  - 1952. Scrapbook re first congressional campaign (Box 85)
  - 1953 (clippings) (Box 85)
  - January-June 1953 (scrapbook) (Box 85)
  - July-December 1953 (scrapbook) (Box 85)
  - 1954 (clippings) (Box 85)
  - 1954 (scrapbooks re assassination attempt) (Volume 3)
  - 1954 (scrapbooks re assassination attempt) (Volume 4)
  - March 1954 (clippings re shooting on floor of House of Representatives), 2 folders (Box 85)
  - January-May 1954 (scrapbook) (Box 85)
  - June-August 1954 (scrapbook) (Box 86)
  - August 1954 (scrapbook re hearings on Hungarian revolt) (Box 86)
  - September-December 1954 (scrapbook) (Box 86)
  - 1954 (scrapbook) (Box 86)
  - 1955 (clippings)
    - Personal (Box 86)
    - CIO-PAC political contributions, 4 folders (Box 86)
    - Eighth Congressional District Republican Party (Box 86)
    - Michigan politics, 8 folders (Box 86)
    - Michigan roads, 4 folders (Box 87)
    - Michigan taxes, 3 folders (Box 87)
  - January-June 1955 (scrapbook) (Box 87)
  - July-December 1955 (scrapbook) (Box 87)
  - 1956 (clippings)
    - Personal (Box 87)
    - Flood control (Box 87)
    - Milk strike, 2 folders (Box 87)
  - January-September 1956 (scrapbook) (Box 87)
  - October-December 1956 (scrapbook) (Box 87)
  - 1957 (clippings), 2 folders (Box 87)
  - January-August 1957 (scrapbook) (Box 87)
  - June-December 1957 (scrapbook) (Box 88)
  - 1958 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - April 1958 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - May 1958 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - June 1958 (clippings), 2 folders (Box 88)
  - July 1958 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - August 1958 (clippings), 3 folders (Box 88)
  - September 1958 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - 1958 (scrapbook) (Box 88)
  - 1959 (clippings) (Box 88)
  - January-July 1959 (scrapbook) (Box 88)
  - June 1959-August 25, 1960 (scrapbooks) (Box 89)
  - August 26-December 1960 (scrapbooks) (Box 90)
  - 1960 (scrapbook re senatorial campaign) (Volume 5)
  - 1961 (clippings)
    - Auto excise tax (Box 90)
    - Bentley and Republicans (Box 90)
    - Health care (Box 91)
    - Michigan in the Civil War (Box 91)
    - Jobless (Box 91)
    - Michigan and Detroit economy (Box 91)
    - Michigan industries (Box 91)
    - Michigan State Legislature, 2 folders (Box 91)
    - Redistricting (Box 91)
    - State Highways (Box 91)
    - Swainson and Democrats (Box 91)
    - Taxes (Box 91)
    - Voting (Box 91)
    - G. Mennen Williams (Box 91)
  - March December 1962 (scrapbooks) (Box 92)
  - October 1962 (scrapbook) (Box 93)
  - 1962 (clippings) (Box 93)
  - 1963 (clippings)-Personal, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - 1963-1966 (clippings)-John Mackie, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - 1963-1966 (clippings)-Patrick McNamara (Box 93)
  - 1963-1965 (clippings)-Neil Staebler (Box 93)
  - 1964 (clippings)-Personal, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - 1964-1966 (clippings)-Philip A. Hart (Box 93)
  - 1965 (clippings) (Box 93)
  - 1966 (clippings) (Box 93)
  - 1967 (clippings) (Box 93)
  - 1968 (clippings) (Box 93)
  - 1969 (clippings) (Box 93)
- Diaries and journals
  Diaries and Journals (2 linear ft.; 1933-1969, scattered) consists of both originals and typescripts of the diaries and journals maintained by Bentley throughout much of his career. The most significant gaps are from 1950 to 1955 and from 1961 to 1966.
  - 1933 (Box 94)
  - 1933 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - 1935 (Box 94)
  - 1935 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - June 30-August 27, 1938 (Box 94)
  - June 30-August 27, 1938 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - March 13, 1940-July 1, 1942 (Box 94)
  - March 13, 1940-July 1, 1942 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - August 1-November 12, 1942 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - 1943, 5 volumes 3 volumes original and 2 volumes of typescript (Box 94)
  - January 8, 1944-September 24, 1944 (Box 94)
  - January 8, 1944-September 24, 1944 (Box 94)
  - January 1, 1945-July 6, 1945 (Box 94)
  - January 1, 1945-July 6, 1945 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - August 1948 (Box 94)
  - December 1-28, 1949 (typescript) (Box 94)
  - 1955 (Box 95)
  - 1956 (Box 95)
  - 1957 (Box 95)
  - 1958 (Box 95)
  - 1959 (Box 95)
  - 1960 (Box 95)
  - 1966 (Box 95)
  - 1967 (Box 95)
  - 1968 (Box 95)
  - 1969 (Box 95)
  - 1955-1959, 1961-1969 (typescript and drafts) (Box 95)
- Miscellaneous 1950s-1960s
  (mainly materials received in1981and later)
  Miscellaneous (7 linear ft., 1950s-1960s, scattered) is an artificially created series of materials donated to the library following Bentley's death. Most notable are topical files reflecting his continuing interest in the Republican Party and the University of Michigan, and a set of hearings and reports from the period when he served on the US House Committee on Foreign Relations.
  - University of Michigan
    - General correspondence (Box 96)
    - College Republican Club (Box 96)
    - Graduate History Club (Box 96)
    - President's Club (Box 96)
  - Topical Files
    - Argus Press (Box 96)
    - Barnes, Norma 1966-1967 (Box 96)
    - California-Hawaii trip 1965 (Box 96)
    - Chamberlain, Charles E., 2 folders (Box 96)
    - Con-Con reunion 1967 (Box 96)
    - Congressional Secretaries Club Official Congressional Handbook 1955-1956 (Box 96)
    - Detroit Bank and Trust Co. (Box 96)
    - Fortieth birthday (Box 96)
    - Griffin, Robert P. (Box 96)
    - Harvey, James (Box 96)
    - Lincoln Day Dinner 1966 (Box 96)
    - Nixon Campaign 1968 (Box 96)
    - Noble, John H. (Box 96)
    - Owosso YMCA (Box 96)
    - Romney, George (Box 96)
    - Staff 1952 (Box 96)
    - Stoddard, Meryl L. ("Description Unknown: A Brochure") (Box 96)
    - Testimonial dinner 1961 (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 96)
  - U.S. House Committee on Foreign Relations
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 97)
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 98)
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 99)
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 100)
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 101)
    - Hearings and reports 1953-1960 (Box 102)
- Audio-Visual Materials